export const CHRISTIANRELIGIOUSSTUDIESA2012 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. On the fourth day of creation God created",
A: "the great sea monsters",
B: "the firmament",
C: "the two great lights",
D: "every flying bird",
answer: "C. the two great lights",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. In the first creation story, the major difference between man and all other living things was that",
A: "every other thing was created after man",
B: "only man was given the power to be fruitful",
C: "all other things were not created male and female",
D: "man was created in the image of the creator",
answer: "D. man was created in the image of the creator",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. How old was Abram when God appeared to him the second time",
A: "75 years",
B: "85 years",
C: "99 years",
D: "105 years",
answer: "C. 99 years",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following was the first directive given to man after God had created him",
A: "Be fruitful and multiply, fill the earth and subdue it",
B: "Go ye into the world and exercise full authority over it",
C: "Be you kind to all creatures of the earth",
D: "Behold I have given you every plant yielding seed",
answer: "A. Be fruitful and multiply, fill the earth and subdue it",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Joseph named his first son 'Manasseh' because God made him",
A: "king in Egypt",
B: "forget his hardship",
C: "a ruler of Israel",
D: "fruitful in his father's land",
answer: "B. forget his hardship",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Moses ran away from Egypt because he",
A: "did not like to be trained in Egypt",
B: "could no longer bear the hunger in the land",
C: "feared the news of his murder would reach the king",
D: "heard a divine call to save his people",
answer: "C. feared the news of his murder would reach the king",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. God provided water for the Israelites by asking Moses to strike the rock of the Wilderness of",
A: "Beersheba",
B: "Red sea",
C: "Sin",
D: "Sinai",
answer: "C. Sin",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Who among the following was to ensure the safety of King Saul in the wilderness of Ziph?",
A: "Joab",
B: "Jonathan",
C: "Abner",
D: "Abimelech",
answer: "B. Jonathan",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Solomon showed lack of wisdom in",
A: "building the temple",
B: "his bilateral agreement with other nations",
C: "engaging in commercial ventures",
D: "marrying foreign wives",
answer: "D. marrying foreign wives",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The action of Rehoboam that led to the division of the kingdom was",
A: "following his father's tyranny",
B: "leading Israel to war",
C: "challenging Jeroboam",
D: "worshipping other gods",
answer: "A. following his father's tyranny",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. When Elijah's sacrifice was consumed by fire at mount camel the people reacted by saying",
A: "'Giving God the glory'",
B: "The Lord is God'",
C: "'Give thanks to the gods'",
D: "'The Lord is to be worshiped'",
answer: "B. The Lord is God",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Joshua gathered all the tribes of Israel for his farewell address at",
A: "Shechem",
B: "Gibeon",
C: "Bethel",
D: "Jordan",
answer: "A. Shechem",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The Israelites under Barak defeated the Canaanite troops led by",
A: "Jael",
B: "Sisera",
C: "Abinoam",
D: "Heber",
answer: "B. Sisera",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. According to Daniel the command of Nebuchadnezzar to worship the golden image amounted to",
A: "profanity",
B: "idolatory",
C: "sacrilege",
D: "abomination",
answer: "B. idolatry",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. 'Your love is like the morning cloud, like the dew that goes early' What did Hosea mean by this statement?",
A: "Israel's relationship with God was shortlived",
B: "Israel did not truly love God as she should",
C: "Israel did have love for other gods",
D: "Israel had no love for God",
answer: "A. Israel's relationship with God was short-lived",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. 'Yet what they are building, if a fox goes up on it he will break down their stone wall' This statement by Tobias was meant to",
A: "taunt and ridicule the Jews",
B: "stop and disgrace the Jews",
C: "tease and punish Nehemiah",
D: "alert and strengthen Nehemiah",
answer: "A. taunt and ridicule the Jews",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Jeremiah viewed the relationship between God and Israel in her youth to be that of",
A: "compassion, sincerity and hope",
B: "obedience, tolerance and mercy",
C: "righteousness, kindness and zeal",
D: "loyalty, love and faithfulness",
answer: "D. loyalty, love and faithfulness",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Darius became convinced of God's power through Daniel's",
A: "constant praying and fasting",
B: "interpretation of mystries",
C: "faithfulness and steadfastness",
D: "fearlessness in the face of difficulties",
answer: "C. faithfulness and steadfastness",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. God addressed Ezekiel as the 'Son of Man'. This phrase emphasizes the prophet's",
A: "humanity",
B: "character",
C: "humility",
D: "elegance",
answer: "A. humanity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. God promised to make the forehead of Ezekiel hard against those of the Israelites. This meant that God would",
A: "strenghthen and equip Ezekiel with courage",
B: "protect and harden Ezekiel",
C: "equip Ezekiel with oracles and power",
D: "give Ezekiel new head and power to heal",
answer: "A. strengthen and equip Ezekiel with courage",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. According to Matthew's account of the baptism of Jesus, the voice from heaven said",
A: "'here is my beloved son'",
B: "'this is my beloved son'",
C: "'thou art my beloved son'",
D: "'see my beloved son'",
answer: "B. this is my beloved son",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. What virtue did the Centurion exhibit in the healing of his servant?",
A: "Forgiveness",
B: "Love",
C: "Compassion",
D: "Faith",
answer: "D. Faith",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Jesus demonstrated his compassion for humanity in all the following miracles except the",
A: "feeding of the five thousand",
B: "healing of the centurion's servant",
C: "feeding of the four thousand",
D: "healing of the paralytic",
answer: "D. healing of the paralytic",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following parables alludes to the existence of a mixture of good and bad people in the church? The",
A: "Wicked Tenants",
B: "Seed growing Secretly",
C: "Wheat and Tares",
D: "Prodigal son",
answer: "C. Wheat and Tares",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Jesus' call of the first four disciples to catch men rather than fish implies that they were to",
A: "be trained to become Rabbis",
B: "convert the Jews into Judaism",
C: "propagate the teachings of Jesus",
D: "win proselytes back to Jesus",
answer: "C. propagate the teachings of Jesus",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. According to the Sermon on the Mount, God's kingdom would be filled with those who were",
A: "mournful",
B: "Meek",
C: "poor in spirit",
D: "hungry and thirsty",
answer: "C. poor in spirit",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. In his Transfiguration, Jesus took with him",
A: "Peter, James and Andrew",
B: "Andrew, Peter and John",
C: "Matthew, James and Peter",
D: "James, John and Peter",
answer: "D. James, John and Peter",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. 'He saved others, he cannot save himself'. This was said by the",
A: "Scribes and elders",
B: "Roman authority",
C: "Crowd of People",
D: "Crucified thieves",
answer: "A. Scribes and elders",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The last words of Jesus on the cross was",
A: "my God, my God, why has Thou forsaken'",
B: "father forgive them their transgression",
C: "father into thy hand i commit my spirit",
D: "God have mercy upon them",
answer: "C. Father into thy hands I commit my spirit",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. What did Jesus do at Jacob's well to occasion a conversation between him and the Samaritan woman? Jesus",
A: "told her about her past life",
B: "drove away her attackers",
C: "asked for water to drink",
D: "drew water for her",
answer: "C. asked for water to drink",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. According to Jesus, the following are true about the Good Shepherd except that he",
A: "lays down his life for the sheep",
B: "has no sheep out of the fold",
C: "does not abandon the sheep to the wolf",
D: "knows the sheep and they know him",
answer: "B. has no sheep out of the fold",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. In His teachings as the True Vine, Jesus maintained that prayers could be answered if the disciples",
A: "confess their sins",
B: "abide in him",
C: "pray constantly",
D: "ask for edifying things",
answer: "B. abide in him",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. On the day of the Pentecost, the apostles were filled with the Holy Spirit and they all",
A: "prophesied",
B: "spoke in tongues",
C: "baptized the converts",
D: "preached to the multitudes",
answer: "B. spoke in tongues",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The Jewish religious sect which did not believe in resurrection were the",
A: "Pharisees",
B: "Zealots",
C: "Sadducees",
D: "Essenes",
answer: "C. Sadducees",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. '...yet the most high does not dwell in houses made with hands...' This defense of Stephen meant that God is",
A: "Omnipotent",
B: "Omnipresent",
C: "Alpha",
D: "Omega",
answer: "B. Omnipresent",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Phillip's flight into Samaria was necessitated by",
A: "the need to convert the Samarians",
B: "directive from the Holy Spirit",
C: "persecution of Christians by Saul",
D: "the stoning of Stephen",
answer: "C. persecution of Christians by Saul",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. 'Tabitha, arise' These were said by Peter during the",
A: "healing of Aeneas from paralysis",
B: "raising of Dorcas from death",
C: "healing of the lame man",
D: "converting of Simon the magician",
answer: "B. raising of Dorcas from death",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Luke described Cornelius as a devout man who feared God because he was",
A: "Hellenist of the Italian Cohort",
B: "Proselyte of Jewish descent",
C: "Greek who favoured Jewish religion",
D: "Proselyte in sympathy with Jewish faith",
answer: "D. Proselyte in sympathy with Jewish faith",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Prior to the day of Pentecost, members that constituted the early Church were",
A: "120",
B: "1,200",
C: "3,000",
D: "4,000",
answer: "A. 120",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Paul's letter to Philemon emphasizes",
A: "humility",
B: "love",
C: "forgiveness",
D: "sincerity",
answer: "C. forgiveness",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Paul believes that spiritual gifts are of great advantage to the Church because they",
A: "enhance the beauty of the Church",
B: "promote growth in diverse ways",
C: "lead to talent development",
D: "help the individual to be active",
answer: "B. promote growth in diverse ways",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. The Phillipians showed their solidarity with Paul while in prison by",
A: "using Ephraphroditus to appeal for his release",
B: "sending gifts to him through Ephraphroditus",
C: "sending envoys from Corinth to defend him",
D: "offering regular sacrifices on his behalf",
answer: "B. sending gifts to him through Ephraphroditus",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. All the following describe Christians in first Peter except",
A: "holy nation",
B: "people living together",
C: "God's own people",
D: "chosen race",
answer: "B. people living together",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. In Corinthians, Paul stated that he was unfit to be called an apostle because he",
A: "could not speak in tongues",
B: "persecuted the Church",
C: "was not one of the twelve",
D: "was a Pharisee",
answer: "B. persecuted the Church",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. According to Paul in second Thessalonians, one of the signs of the second coming would be",
A: "revelation of man of lawlessness",
B: "an explosion of world population",
C: "increasing rate of fake disciples",
D: "flagrant violation of God's law",
answer: "A. revelation of man of lawlessness",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Peter described Christians as a chosen race of God because they are to",
A: "Declare God's wonderful deeds",
B: "become ordained pastors",
C: "lead a new life",
D: "displace the jews in God's rating",
answer: "A. declare God's wonderful deeds",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. According to Paul's teaching in Galatians, Christians become sons of God by",
A: "having faith in Jesus christ",
B: "adoption of Judaism",
C: "being Abraham's descendants",
D: "works of faith",
answer: "A. having faith in Jesus Christ",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. According to Peter, doing the right thing is a way of expressing",
A: "our rights",
B: "our freedom",
C: "faith in Christ",
D: "dislike for evil",
answer: "C. faith in Christ",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Paul's letter to Philemon was written to",
A: "support Onesimus as he returned to his master",
B: "order him to take back his slave",
C: "blame Onesimus for stealing from his master",
D: "request Philemon to free his slave",
answer: "A. support Onesimus as he returned to his master",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. According to Peter, Christians who suffer for Christ should not be ashamed but should",
A: "glorify God",
B: "be encouraged",
C: "be patient",
D: "be grateful",
answer: "A. glorify God",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]